Today we're going to be learning how to play Portal, a game by Valve Software.
A company with which I have no affiliation.
Now here we are in the 6th test chamber, where things get a little bit more complicated still.
We can see there's a new icon that lights up here.
We've got this little circular energy ball, which can hit me and kill me, which isn't a good thing.
And then there's the circular energy ball can also go into a power conduit where the ball provides power to change something about the level.
So, from here on out we're going to have to be dealing with these things quite a bit.
Now if we look over here, this is a power ball dispenser.
And you can see that the power balls bounce back and forth between portals which are closed or the wall or the dispenser, but they only last a certain amount of time.
After they bounce back and forth enough times, they'll dissipate and you'll have to get another one.
So, you have to take that into account when you're thinking about transporting the balls from one place to another.
Now, this orange portal is closed because we haven't placed a blue portal yet.
But as soon as we place a blue portal this will open and this ball will go into the orange portal and come out of the blue portal wherever we place it.
So, here's a power ball receptacle and what we want to do, as the icon shows, is get the ball to go into that thing.
What we need to do then, is place a blue portal above it so that when the power ball goes into the orange it will come out of the blue and go right into the receptacle.
I guess it went in there while we weren't looking and it activated this, which lowered this elevator which we can get on.
And now it's going to allow us to move on to the next test chamber.
So, this idea of placing portals at different places and times to get balls into the power generators is a critical concept to moving forward in the world of Portal.
And that's this test chamber.